Resume

Aigerim Dzhanyshpekova (Aika)

Cell: +1 (206) 823 6429 Location: Seattle, WA

e-mail: outcards12@gmail.com

Summary

I am a Junior Software Engineer with two years of experience in web development and programming. My professional journey is characterized by flexibility and creativity in problem-solving. I work effectively both independently and as part of a team, and I am currently seeking opportunities to apply my skills in new projects aimed at developing innovative software for advancements in the field of AI. I look forward to the possibility of contributing to the success of your company.

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Styled Components, React.js, Redux, Axios, Node.js, Python, Git.

Work experience

September 2023 - Currently working

Software Engineering at Springboard

- Implemented a chat application for users using React, Express.js, Node.js, which helped reduce client response time by 30%.
- Built CRUD app for customer dashboard using React.js, JavaScript.
- Implemented material and semantic UI to applications improving web app speed by 20%.

September 2023 – Currently working

Working with students

- I am a volunteer helping students who study programming. My tasks include:
- Expanding and deepening knowledge and skills in programming using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux.;
- Enriching systematized knowledge in computer science necessary for developing and creating applications using design tools and databases;
- Creating conditions for activating students' cognitive activity, forming their practical experience in using programming methods when solving tasks, and stimulating their research activities in the process of mastering the discipline.

January 2013-2016

Marketing Director at Kyrgyz Concept Ltd. (The Kyrgyz Republic)

- Reduced company operating expenses by 12% by successfully transitioning 80% of print materials to digital, improving workflow for 500 employees within a few months.
- Executed market entry for the "Tourist Guide" product in foreign countries while managing the project remotely, attracting over a thousand new partners for the company.
- Fully oversaw the company's rebranding process and the development of a new website, which subsequently demonstrated high demand and contributed to attracting new clients.

Education background

Self-taught software engineer

Partial college education in Marketing. Kyrgyz National University, Bishkek, Kyrgyz Republic (2007-2011)

Associate of Science in Banking and Finance. College at the Kyrgyz Economic University, Bishkek, Kygryz Republic (2007-2010)

Languages: Kyrgyz - native, Russian - fluent, English - good